# SAMANTHA INGRAM

## Archaeologist

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### HERITAGE CONSULTANT, WESSEX ARCHAEOLOGY

07/2015 - Present

Wessex Archaeology is a leading provider of heritage services to a range of sectors and clients across the UK. I worked on commercial heritage consultancy projects, undertook desk based research, heritage planning guidance and conservation policy, as well as assessed impacts to the setting and significance of heritage assets.

# JUNIOR ARCHAEOLOGIST, ARCHAEOLOGICAL SITE OF CARTHAGE 10/2014 - 07/2015

After having worked on Tunisia's famous archaeological site as a trainee in 2009, I had the great honor of being able to manage a discrete area of work, restoring some recently discovered hot springs.

#### **ENGLISH SPEAKING GUIDE, MAC EMPÚRIES**

06/2013 - 10/2014

I spent a year as one of the English Speaking Guides at the Empúries archaeological site located in the northern mediterranean coast of Spain. Empúries is the only archaeological site in the Iberian Peninsula where there remains a Greek - Emporion colony. In this enclave, there are remains from a Roman city that was founded in the early 1st century BC, as well as structures from a Roman military camp installed during the previous century.

# ARCHAEOLOGY TRAINEE, ARCHAEOLOGICAL SITE OF CARTHAGE 07/2009 -09/2009

My internship consisted in fieldwork, helping the District of Tunis Archaeological staff on the restoration and maintenance work at the Archaeological Site of Carthage which has been protected by Unesco Heritage Program for Historic Monuments since 1985. Carthage was founded in the 9th century B.C. on the Gulf of Tunis. From the 6th century onwards, it developed into a great trading empire covering much of the Mediterranean and was home to a brilliant civilization. During the long course of the Punic Wars, Carthage occupied territories belonging to Rome. The Romans finally destroyed their rival in 146 B.C. A second Roman settlement was then established on the original ruins of Carthage.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **ARCHAEOLOGY**

UCL Institute of Archaeologys 09/2012 - 05/2013

#### **ANTHROPOLOGY MRES**

University College London 09/2007 - 08/2011

#### **GCE ADVANCED LEVEL**

N. Bridge House Senior Canonbury 09/2000 - 06/2007

- ≥ samingramarch4@gmail.com
- **\** +44 077 0007 0004
- Paristol, England, UK
- onlineresume.us/samingram4

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Archaeologist with 9 years of experience conducting desk based research as well as fieldwork on historical archaeological sites such as Carthage and Empúries.

Currently, leveraging my greatest skills in analysis, research, observation and conservation to excel in my work on commercial heritage consultancy projects, as well as guiding heritage planning and promoting policies on conservation.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**



### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic - Limited Working Proficiency English - Native/Bilingual Proficiency Spanish - Full Professional Proficiency

French - Full Professional Proficiency

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### + Preservation of Wooly Mammoth Skeleton

One of my most recent greatest achievements was preserving a Wooly Mammoth skeleton while working with Wessex Archaeology.

#### + Exploration of Palmyra Archaeological Site

An oasis in the Syrian desert, north-east of Damascus, Palmyra contains the monumental ruins of a great city that was one of the most important cultural centres of the ancient world

Scan the QR code to view my online resume with more information about my career: greatest skills, references, and more.

